In this problem, we're going
to look at how to infer a
continuous random variable from
a discrete measurement.
And the continuous random
variable that we're interested
in in this problem is q, which
is given by this PDF.
It's 6q times 1 minus
q for a q between
0 and 1 and 0 otherwise.
And here is a graph of
what it looks like.
It just kind of has
this curve shape.
And it's symmetric.
And it's peak is at 1/2.
And the way to interpret
q is q is the
unknown bias of a coin.
So the bias of a coin, the
probability of heads of that
coin is somewhere
between 0 and 1.
We're not sure exactly
what it is.
And here is our, say, prior
belief about how this random
bias is distributed.
And we're going try to infer
what this bias is by flipping
the coin and observing whether
or not we got heads or tails.
And because of that, the
measurement, or the
observation that we
get, is discreet.
Either we get heads,
or we get tails.
And we model that using a
discrete random variable x,
which is, in this case, it
turns out it's just a
Bernoulli random variable,
either 0 or 1.
And the model that we have is
that, if we knew what this
bias q was, if we knew that it
was a little q, then this
coin, I mean, it behaves as if
it was a coin with that bias.
So the probability of getting
heads, or the probability that
x equals 1, is just equal
to q, which is the bias.
And the probability that it's
equal to 0 is 1 minus q.
So that's just our model
of how the coin works.
We can also write this another
way, as just more like a
conditional PMF.
So the conditional PMF of x,
given q of little x, is q, if
x is 1, 1 minus q, if x equals
0, and 0 otherwise.
Just a more compact way
of writing this.
All right, so what we want to
do in this problem is find
this conditional PDF.
What is the conditional
PDF of q given x?
So we observe what x is,
either a 0 or 1.
And we want to know now, given
that information, given that
measurement, what is the
new distribution of q
the bias of the coin?
And to do that, well, we
apply Bayes' rule.
And remember, Bayes' rule, it
consists of several terms.
The first one is the numerator,
which is our prior
initial belief, so which is
just the regular PDF of q,
times the conditional
PMF of x given q.
All right, so because we have a
continuous variable that we
want to infer from a discreet
measurement, we use this
variation of Bayes' rule, where
we have a PDF here and a
conditional PMF here.
And the denominator is--
well, it's the PMF of x.
And of course, we can take
this PMF of x, this
denominator, and expand it,
using the law of total
probability where the PMF of x,
you can think of it as you
can get x with a combination of
lots of different possible
values of the bias q.
And so we just calculate
all those
possibilities and integrate.
And what we want to integrate
here is q, so we want to
integrate-- remember to keep
in mind the limits of
integration.
And this is just referenced
by the limits of what
the PDF of q is.
OK.
All right, so now we're asked to
find what this value is for
x equals to 0 or 1 and
for all values of q.
And the values of q we care
about are the ones
between 0 and 1.
So let's focus on the two
different possibilities for x.
So the first one is, let's
look at the case where x
equals 1 first.
And then now let's just
plug-in what all these
different terms should be.
Well, the PDF of
q we're given.
And of course, we're looking
here at q between 0 and 1, so
within that range.
The PDF of q is just
6q times 1 minus q.
And the conditional PMF of x
where we know that from our
model, because we're looking at
the case where x equals 1.
That conditional
PMF is just q.
And the denominator is really
the same as the numerator,
except you integrate it.
So it's the integral from
0 to 1 of 6q times 1
minus q times q dq.
OK.
And now we can simplify this.
So under the numerator,
we have integral--
sorry, 6q squared
times 1 minus q.
And then the bottom we have
the integral of 6q squared
minus q cubed, d cubed
from 0 to 1.
And now this is just
some calculus now.
So we still have the numerator
6q squared times 1 minus q.
The denominator, we
have 2q cubed--
that would give us the
6q squared term--
minus 6/4 q to the fourth.
And we integrate that
from 0 to 1.
OK.
And what does that give us?
We get 6q squared 1 minus
q still on the top.
And the bottom, we get--
well the 0--
the case where it's
0, it's just 0.
The case where it's 1, it's
2 minus 3/2, so it's 1/2.
So really, it just becomes
12 q squared 1 minus q.
And of course, this only true
when q is between 0 and 1.
All right, so the case
where it's equal to
1, we have our answer.
And it turns out that, if
you plot this, what
does it look like?
It looks something like this
where the peak is now at 2/3.
So how do you interpret this?
The interpretation is that what
you have is you observe
that you've got, actually,
heads on this toss.
So that is evidence that
the bias of the coin
is relatively high.
So it's relatively more likely
to get heads with this coin.
So q, in that case, you would
believe that it's more likely
to be higher than 1/2.
And it turns out that, when you
go through this reasoning
and the Bayes' rule, what
you get is that
it looks like this.
And the peak is now at 2/3.
And you can repeat this exercise
now with the case
where x is 0.
So when x is 0, you still get
the same term here, 6q 1 minus
q, but the conditional PMF
is now the-- you want the
conditional PMF when x equals
0, which is now 1 minus q.
So you get 1 minus q here.
And now this term becomes 6q
times 1 minus q squared.
And so really, the bottom is
also 6q times 1 minus q
squared dq.
And if you go through the same
sort of calculus, what you get
is that, in this case,
the answer is
12q 1 minus q squared.
So let me rewrite what
the first case was.
The first case, when x equals
1 was equal to 12q
squared 1 minus q.
So they look quite similar,
except that this one has q
squared, this one has
1 minus q squared.
And if you take this one, the
case where you observe a 0,
and you plot that, it
turns out it looks
something like this.
And this actually doesn't look
like it, but it should be the
peak is at 1/3.
And so you notice, first of all,
that these are symmetric.
There's some symmetry
going on.
And this interpretation in this
case is that, because you
observed 0, which corresponds to
observing tails, that gives
you evidence that the bias of
the coin is relatively low, or
the probability of getting
heads with this coin is
relatively low, which pushes
your belief about q towards
the smaller values.
OK, so it turns out that
this distribution, this
distribution, and the original
distribution of q, all fall
under family of distributions
called the beta distribution.
And they're parameterized by
a couple of parameters.
And it's used frequently to
model things like the bias of
a coin, or anything that's a
random variable that's bounded
between 0 and 1.
OK, so this problem allowed us
to get some more exercise with
Bayes' rule, this continuous
discrete
version of Bayes' rule.
And if you go through all the
steps, you'll find that it's
relatively straightforward to
go through the formula and
plug in the different parts of
the terms and go through a
little bit of calculus
and find the answer.
And it's always good to go
back, once you find the
answer, to look at it a little
bit and make sure that
actually makes sense.
So you can convince yourself
that it's not
something that looks--